Phone: +254708950069

E-mail: brimwene@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brian-imwene-4990b7117/

Brian Imwene Okiring'

Summary

Experienced self-taught front-end engineer working my way to becoming a full-stack engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the software development industry. Skilled in HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Vue, Mongo, Database Administration, and Database Design. Strong professional background with a Bachelor's degree focused in Information Technology from J.K.U.A.T as well as being a full-time student at FreeCodeCamp.org. Open to project collaborations with strong background in project management and customer relations.

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design

Programming languages

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- React

- Vue
- WordPress
- Node
- Tailwind

Experience

ICT Volunteer – January 2020 to present

Youth Welfare Association • Nairobi, Kenya.

Since January 2020, I have been volunteering at the above-named NGO. I worked as part of the team that built as well as maintains their website.

Front-end Engineer – February 2017- Present MobiweCraft Limited • Nairobi, Kenya.

As a web consultant, I specialized in the development of custom mobile and Web based Solutions targeting cooperates as well as individuals. Some of the roles included:

- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with senior developer to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

Technical lead - October 2016-February 2017 **Safetek limited • Nairobi, Kenya**.

My main task, carried out between October 2016 and January 2017 was to lead a team of developers to come up with the first of a kind, fully functional cashless system for the transport industry.

We worked with 2NK Sacco (A public transport leader) and came up with a platform that enabled their members to access as well as transact via web as well as mobile app running on an android based P.O.S (Point of Sale) machine.

IT Intern – March 2012–May 2012 Kenya Power • Nairobi, Kenya.

Worked in the Kenya Power, IT department Nairobi region for three months between March and May 2012. Experienced in support desk team program installation including: *Data base applications*

Include Oracle Win, UNIX and Power Builder. End user applications Operating systems, ICS, LCA, DCS, IMS, OFFICE, DTMMS, SAP, TMS, FDBS, SPS, LRA, antivirus and CITRIX.

Licenses and Certifications

2021 - freeCodeCamp.org

Responsive Web Design Certificate - Computer Software Engineering

Education

2014-2018 - Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Second Class Honor's Upper Division

2014-2018 - Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Computer Engineering

Second Class Honor's Upper Division

2006-2009 - Mang'u High School

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Mean Grade A(Plain) 83/84 Points

2002-2005 - Fountain Gate Preparatory School

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education Mean Grade A 432/500 Points

References

Robert Sifuna - National Coordinator Youth Welfare Association

Telephone number: +254713742777

Nevile Masheti - Founder MobiweCraft Limited

Telephone Number: +254713976532

Sammy Ndegwa - Executive Director Safetek Limited

P.O. Box 71654-00622

Telephone number: +254722454865

James nyangate - Principal IT & T officer Kenya Power, Electricity house

Telephone Number: +254724281410

Fr. Daniel Kariuki - Chaplain, Mang'u High School P.O.

BOX 314, Thika.

Telephone Number: +254727928977, +254733747605